<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sarama Blog</title><link>https://blog.sarama.xyz/posts/</link><description>Sarama Blog (Posts)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:28:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.sarama.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dogs Setting Boundaries</title><link>https://blog.sarama.xyz/posts/dogs_setting_boundaries/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 23:28:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://blog.sarama.xyz/posts/dogs_setting_boundaries/</guid><description>&lt;p>Much like people, dogs learn to set boundaries with other dogs &amp;amp; other people. They do this as both a sense of self-protection and to ensure healthy social interactions. As someone who has two dogs, I see this constantly especially in the interaction between my Doberman mix, Kali, and my chihuahua, Riley (who I secretly believe is a cat in a dog’s body).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since bringing Riley home seven years ago, she’s taught us about her personal space being a top priority. Every so often, a misstep will receive a small growl that will grow more pronounced as the foot lingers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have two dogs. I have a Doberman mix and a chihuahua. My chihuahua, Riley, acts like a cat and doesn’t like people besides a couple people who are constantly over at our house. We have had Riley for 7 years and she has some boundaries that she has set for everyone. We cannot get in her bubble and if we do, she definitely lets us know with a growl. Sometimes it is a complete accident and I am sitting on the couch and my head touches her back. She gives me a little growl and I know to move.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is very interesting that dogs have a way to set boundaries with their owners. My sister in law&amp;rsquo;s dog has also set boundaries with their 2 year old. My nephew likes to play rough sometimes and wants to pet his dog. Most of the time it isn’t an issue but sometimes the dog doesn’t want to be played with that way and lets out a little bark or growl to let him know that she wants to be left alone. Nothing hostile at all in this action but she is setting a boundary for the family to recognize. It is amazing how dogs are able to get a point across without speaking a word to their owners.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>